Hi everyone once again welcome to DBS you
take myself Gaurav and through this particular
video of today we are going to understand
how you can draw a line on any image
and along with this
how you can draw a box on any image here
now where do these lines and boxes
come on your camera like first let me
show you how they look so see I have
an image here I have
made a box on this image and here there is another
image on which what have I done is
drawn a line now where do these two
things come, basically where are these things
taken so this thing is used
for face detection app means
whenever you have to make an app from the page or
you want to get someone to follow you then this is taken for you
now let
me show you this live practical here
how you will find the camera inside the face detection app
so see what you do by going inside your system you do a
simple thing open the camera
yes here as soon as you open the camera then
Look inside the camera, your
face detection will start and you will
see a blue box. Now
this blue rectangle box that you can
see here, just how it was
created and look, this is also
moving with my face, but how it will move
with the face, we will
see in our upcoming video, but
before that we will see
how this box will be created on any object.
What things do we need for this box,
we are going to talk about all those things here, so let
me tell you practically
how it is going to be created, so for this we have
two functions, they will be needed,
first we will talk about the image, so
look, we have a lot of
different types of images here and
I want that
this image of Ranveer Kapoor that you have, I
want to create a box on it here, so I will be able to create this box here,
now see how we can create this box, so
for that, let's go
inside our piping file where we  By using the cv2
model, we are going to reduce all this. So
for this, what am I going to do here? I am going to
import it and
how to import it. C2, cb2 means open the
model and we will import it here. Now
here we will have to get the image first of all,
then we will have to place the rake channel on it. So
now how
can we get the image? So for that, I am going to read the
function. So for that, first of all I will have to
create a variable. So, look, here I am
creating an image with the name of all underscore img. That means I have an old image which
I am taking right now. Here I am going to
create a new image by making a rectangle on it. So,
I have given the old image here. I have
done that.
Look, here I am going to read the function cv2 or
cv2.im. You have the read function here.
Now to read out the image file, we have to create a read file. So,
what is the name of the
image file here? So, the name of the image file is IMG3. And
my python file is also lying here. That
means both.  If it is in the same folder, then
I don't need to give the address, I can
directly use it, so
Img three here means which image file is it,
here is this file of three,
here I am giving three in the image file, so
what is this of my image, it has been read,
now this read file, if we
see it, then its height and weight is very
high, so I will have to make it
smaller according to my system, that means I will have to
recise, so here I have old
image
cc tu dot here
we have a function of recise by which we can
recise the image, now if we want to recise the image,
then which image do we have to do, so
I said here the old image that you have, you have to
recise it and what do you want to convert it into,
here I would like to convert it in height and weight, so
its
width is 300, and
its height, I will go to ₹ 600,
once this image is uploaded, it shows this image once, so to show it,
I will do that here
cv2.im show yes I am doing it with show function
and inside it I will
call the frame which is here, that means the name of a frame
place this old image of ours. Now if
I want to show this image, then for the image
I will have to use the wait key here to close the window,
so I
will do it here, wait key and inside the wait key I will
pass zero. Now what is this wait key,
what is image show, so
all our previous lecturers,
I have explained them to you in great detail,
now after that I will
do it here CBT tu dot here
destroy all windows so that I
can close all the windows, so I
took destroy all windows here and closed it and ran it, while running
see, my image has come
below, as soon as I open it, it has come
now its width is
very less, so we increase its width a little
and make the width a little
around 500 pixels here, so
I will do its  With this, if I change it and
run it with 500 pixels, then
see, I can see this image quite well
here and I can extend it from 600
and if I take it above ₹ 700 once, then
see what kind of image is coming,
this image is showing me very well,
everything is showing inside it, now
what I have to do here is to create a box here,
which will be
different for you, it can be of green color or
what I have to do is to cut its hair,
so I have to draw a line here,
now how can we draw this line, let's
first understand it here, so see
inside the image, if you want to draw a
line, then for that, you have a function
named line inside cv2, which you can use here
and inside that you can
see different parameters, you
can prepare it here, so now I am
creating a new image here, so I will
create a variable named new underscore img,
which will create a new image, now for this
Inside cv2 dot here is the line function, as
I told you, inside this line function
you have to give different parameters on the
basis of which your line is
drawn here. Now what are those parameters? So you have
these parameters,
which you have to use and on the
basis of them you do your work.
Now see, let me take you to their parameters,
so what are their parameters? These are the
parameters that you have to
give here. First of all, what is the image here, your old image, on
top of which you draw a line here, that means you have
an original image,
what do we have to do with our line on it, we are overlapping it,
so basically we are leaving our line on top of the original image, so
for that we will give that old image here inside the image,
so I have given the old image, now
after this what is pt1 pt2 and what is color,
we are going to understand this thing here, we will
talk about color, we will talk about thickness
here and after that we will have the last A
about line type  So
now let's first understand point van and pt2 here,
what is this point pt2, so
this line that you have here, these
two lines are formed between these two points,
so what do you have to find out the cardinate of this point, you have to find out the
coordinates, meaning you have to give the x coordinates for
it, in which you have to give
pt1 means 0.1 number in van and
you have to give this inside pt2, inside this point
number tu, within which
you have to give the cardinate of x,
now what is this x to a card net, so
for basics, the distance between this point and this point,
means the coordinates of this point from this point,
here are called coordinates, see this
cardinate starts from 0, let's
talk about the coordinates of this point, let's go
00 here and if you move
inside it in this direction, then you will get
inside the x axis and if you move in this direction, then
what will you get, it will come inside the a-axis,
so I have to calculate this  If you want to walk till the point, it
means you will get some coordinates of the x axis
and if you want to walk within this success, then
some points of the a axis will also come
here, so on that basis you will get this pt1,
what will you get, that means
you will have two lines, if you want to draw a line, then
what will you have to do for that, two
points are going to be retired, so
let's draw two points, so first I do
one thing, I
look at my image once again
and according to that I estimate the point pt2,
how much it is going to be, see, I
run it here, so see, this total
overall width here is what is it,
500 is given here, means the
overall width that is being formed here is
what is it, if we
talk of 500, it is around 700, so look, to
walk from here to here, it will cost me approximately
150 and 150 will be spent here, so almost
I will run at the rate of 150,
so here I will calculate its  There is a four head, I am going to
draw a line on this four head of
green colour, basically we are going to reduce it, so
here one point will come and here
one point will come, on the basis of these two points we will
reduce, so let's make one point and one point,
two points here, so
inside this, I am preparing the new image inside it, so if I
talk about pt1 inside the new image, then how much did I have to move inside the x-axis inside pt1,
so I said let's
move around 200 here and after that
inside the A axis, I think it will be
50 to 60 here, if there is no around here, then
we will change it, so I
gave this pt1, now next here we have to
move forward inside the x axis, so overall how many images do
you have 500, okay let's make it 150
because it will be too much, okay I will make it
50 in 100 and four red around
you have around 200 here, of different
50, so it should be approximately 400 I
think  50 for 200 so I will make it 250,
reduce it by one and make it 100, so 250
and its width I will make it 600
now next you have the color,
what do you have, it is in bijiyar RGB
here, yes you have the color in BRG
here, next time I
told you the same way, you can get its color code,
that is you can get the color here, so here
I will go to the internet and
get the BRG color here, so if we talk about its color,
what is the color here, it is busy and there is
color here, basically if we talk, then
you have to get the color of bijiyar,
so I will bring the color of bijiyar
here, ok I will take the color and
inside the bijiyar color you will
see all the colors that you have, so you
can take any of these by taking a good pick from there,
inside this, if we talk about bijiyar color,
here you will get your different colors,
in which you  You will
get colors according to many different charts,
so I want this color from you, yes I want this
color zero 255, okay, I want green color,
anyway, you want zero 25,
so I will put this color code here,
okay, I have put the right color and let's
talk about the thickness, how much thickness do I want here, I
mean how thick do I want your line, so with the
line, basically I do it
around four here and now if I
talk about line tag line type, then
we have many different
light types,
you can choose any of these line types
and can also choose their code, so I am
basically going to take four here, I will
take its code, now this new image of mine has been shared,
so what do I do, I replace this new image with
this old image
and then I do mine, so see,
this is my line, so the line has become very
small, it has gone very
high, so basically I have to
bring it down first and after that, I have to raise it a
little  We also need to increase the with as well, so let me decrease it and
bring it down, which means you have to go
inside the A axis, so to
come below the axis, I will make it 200
and I will also make this one here 200, so
see in the A axis, it has not
come exactly, but yes we have a little bit of A, so it
means it will not work less than 200, so I will have to make
it 1090, only then it will move a little
higher.  So what will I do with 100, I will make it
90 here, now I have to increase its with
here, so I have to make with so I will run it
once and see that it is running fine, yes it is
running fine from here but there is a
little problem for the point here, so that will have to be
increased a little, so by increasing it I will
reduce it, I will make it around 400
and then turn it, see it has become too much, I have to reduce it a little
here, so I will make it
350 and see how much is there in 350,
turn it, it did
not come out exactly, I will have to increase it a little, so I will
run it by making it 60 here,
exactly so see what we have
done with this, the line has been formed above the four,
now if you want, you can draw a line a little above it,
like the line is above it, you
mean
you will have to change its A axis
and by changing it I will make it 170
and run it here, so see
this exact and online
type of yours is visible here and
according to the line type  So the line that you have is
already drawn. So in this way you can draw a line on any
character that you have or any
image that you have here.
Now here next let's talk about the line on the
image. So we have drawn it.
If I had to draw a rectangle, then
how would I draw it. So for that let's go
back to the other program. So
what am I doing here? Let's just
copy it and paste it
here again. Now I will talk about the
rectangle. So if we talk about the rectangle,
what will happen inside the cases of the rectangle?
This formula here will
change and in its place you will feel that the
finger function will be the rectangle
function. The rectangle function
also has the same parameters. You
have the image pt1 pt2 color thickness line types
etc. everything is the same. So inside this also there are the
same parameters that you have inside it. So
I will
put the same parameters back again. But now the
point that is inside it.  The pt2 one gets changed,
how does this point pt2 change,
like this box, inside this box which will be
pt1, this city van, you will have this
point, that means your pt1 will come to you
tomorrow, inside which you
can see the mobile number of x, secondly if you
put this pt2 point, in between this,
what will you do, you will create this box here and
this will become pt2 and inside which
your mobile number of x will be created here,
inside this then you can create your box like this here,
let's now
rate it, so this
point which you have, like if I
run the first image above once again, it
is here, now I go that all the
hair etc. here should
come together inside the box, that means
how can his face be, that means Ranveer Kapoor's
face, after that I have to frame the box here, so I
can do that
easily, now see how, for that, first
I will have to go very far back in x,
so I go to 100  And in the A axis
I will have to go very high so
what do I do, I will turn it around 50,
right now let's talk about here, I have to go in this direction
completely, so completely you have
360 ​​in the X accessory, I have to go down a little
further here, so to go down
I will turn it around to 300, around, okay, let's
keep the color the same as the old one, the thickness is
also the same, you can change the line type a little,
this time under the line type we are taking 16 here, so
you can take the line type as 16 here, and
as soon as you run it, a box will appear with you,
so the overall width of the box is
not correct a little and I have to
bring it here a little too, so you
can change the coordinates of its access and A axis, so
from the top, this is the correct marking,
but it should come down a little more, so I will
take it a little further down, so there was a
problem in the A axis, try doing 500
here, okay, yours is almost correct a little.  If we
reduce 50 more here, it will become less, so I will make
it 450, if it does
not come exactly, then it will come around ₹ 470
and I will have to reduce a little here too, so I will make
70 from 400 and I have to
move it here, so 60 plus 40, let's
reduce it to 400, this also
run a little bit here, it is correct,
but a little more of this here, so in
this way you can adjust it according to your requirement, like this we
will do 30 here, this our
whole face is perfectly
covered up, here this thing is
taken in less at the time of face detection app, in this way boxes etc. are made
and your face that is happening,
that box etc. can be created here from the face of the face,
right, but first
you should know which
functions you can use to reduce all this
and what parameters can be given, so
as I have mentioned here  Ranveer Singh's name has been
written here. Now if you
want to write text on it, you
can also write text on it. If
you want to write text etc. here, you
can see the text. Let me
tell you how to write text on it. If I want to
write a text here, inside which
I am giving its name, then see, the
method to see the text has been explained
very well by us in our last video lecturers.
So you can
see that once as well. Here, inside which there is tax,
I will quickly tell you
how to write the tax. So I will create a variable named t h t
and after that I will put the
text here by using CBT tu dot.
Here, through food tax, I will
also put what do you have inside the tax, image
tags origin, after that font face, after that
font scale color, if there are many things
that you can put here, right,
I quickly put many things together,
which are needed here, so
first of all let's talk about the image, so
which image of ours will come less here, old  The image will be
reduced, next we will get the
text, inside the text I have to
write here Wask, so when did I take WS,
now after that your original meaning from where should I
start, I will have to
give x axis here, so I will have to
give x axis here, so I
reduce it once, I have to show it at the top, that means
my start from here has to be
shown from here and above this I have to show
basically the text, so on the right, above this,
like its font scale, that font
scale, for example, I make it four here, so
four you will have a little bigger pixels, so let's
reduce it once, so I start
from 100 x axis and
increase it a little up in the a axis,
so let's make it around 20, right, so
I wrote this, so if we talk about font face, then
I will keep the font face here,
we have covered all these things in our last video,
if you have not seen that, then
you can go and see it, okay and if we talk about font color,
I will keep the font color green,
right, what am I doing,
keep the font color green  I am going to use this color code for green color. So
this is our color code for green color. Here I will
take this color code. You have
our font color. And if we
talk about thickness, then
I will keep it around four. The thickness of
four is the end of your line type.
If you keep it inside the line type, then I am
making the line at 16 only. And
what am I doing with the bottom origin? Should I make it false here
because I do not want to print it upside down. I want to
print it right.
I will have to make it false here. Now
this image with text is already here. So this
image with text will have to be given here. So
I will create a TXT with the name of text underscore
IMG here. And
here text underscore will be
available with the name of IMG. If I turn it on, then
look, your W written above is very
big. So I will have to make it very
small. So I will not have to move it a little. So
this is happening because of the font scale. So
I will open the font scale.
See, it is very small. Let me
bring it down a little.  So
to bring it down, instead of 20, I will make it
50 right and see, it is already passed
and let's reduce it by one, let's make it 40,
run, see, W is already skipped,
now it will be better if we color it red,
anyway your color is
busy here, so if I reduce
it, let's make it 255 and
we will turn it to zero here, so see,
and SK you have already written A here, in this way you
can write your name etc. on anyone here and
if I make it 45, then see, Thoughts
good, it looks very good, here the
name can also be written like this, see, the
name is written on it, here the tax, so
you can perform all these things here, so I
think I hope you must have understood
how to make a line and
how you
can show the name with the rectangle box here, so
in today's video, we have got these two things
here, that's all.  Till
then you can join us for our next video Ye Bhi Ban Rahi Hai
Til De Good Bye
[Prashaas]
[Music]